刑法により禁じられた犯罪行為＞
＜５年以下の懲役 または➡
50万円以下の
罰金に処せられます＞
＜後悔しても 元には戻せない＞
不正視聴!?
(マダラ)16年前の 九尾の妖狐襲来。
The attack of the Nine-Tailed
Fox Demon 16 years ago.
あらぬ疑いが かけられた。
Suspicion fell on them.
うちはが主権を狙って 反逆を
起こそうとしたのではないか と。
That the Uchiha had revolted
and sought to take power.
以降 うちはへの監視は
暗部により徹底され➡
As a result,
the Uchiha was put under the strict
surveillance of the Anbu Black Ops,
一族の居住地は
里の片隅へと追いやられ➡
and they were forced to relocate
to the outskirts of the village.
They became totally estranged.
隔離さながらの状態になった。
ヤツらの不信は わだかまりを生み
疑いは やがて 現実となっていく。
Their distrust bred hatred
and eventually,
their suspicions became reality.
うちは一族は クーデターを企んだ。
里を乗っ取るために…。
The Uchiha clan plotted
a coup d'état to take over the village...
そして 木ノ葉上層部は➡
The higher-ups in Hidden Leaf Village
planted a spy within the Uchiha clan.
うちは一族の中に
スパイを送り込んだ。
That spy was your older brother...
それがお前の兄
うちはイタチだ。
Itachi Uchiha.
そこから
イタチの地獄は始まったのだ。
From that moment,
Itachi's suffering began.
(サスケ)うちはが クーデター？
イタチが… スパイだと!?
A coup d'état by the Uchiha?
Itachi was...a spy?
お前は うちはにいながら
何も知らされていない。
Despite being an Uchiha,
you were kept in the dark.
まだ 幼かったからだ。
Because you were still young.
だが これらは真実だ。
But it's all true...
お前の父親 フガクは
そのクーデターを率いる首謀者だった。
Your father, Fugaku,
was the mastermind behind the plot.
そして イタチは 父の命により
暗部に入り込んだ スパイだった。
And your brother, Itachi,
was ordered by your father
to spy on the Anbu Black Ops.
((フガク : イタチ… お前は
一族と里の中枢をつなぐ➡
Itachi... You also serve as
the Uchiha clan's pipeline
to the Village nerve center.
(パイプ役でもあるのだ。
それは わかってるな？))
You know that, don't you?
(マダラ)だが それは 逆だった。
However...it was actually the opposite.
イタチは 里側に
うちはの情報を流していた。
Itachi was working for the village,
feeding them information
about the Uchiha.
He was what they call
a double agent.
俗に言う 二重スパイというヤツだ。
それが どれほどの重荷か
お前には 想像もできないだろう。
You can't even imagine
what a heavy burden that is to bear.
Why?! Why did Itachi betray the Uchiha?
なぜ… なぜ
イタチは うちはを裏切る!?
It may be hard for you
to understand,
戦争を見ていないお前には
理解できないかもしれないな。
not having witnessed the horrors of war.
第三次忍界大戦…。
The Third Great Ninja War...
When Itachi was merely
four years old,
イタチは わずか ４歳で
多くの人の死を目にしてしまった。
he witnessed the deaths
of many people.
戦争を経験するには 幼すぎた。
He was too young to experience war.
War is hell...
戦争は地獄だ…。
That trauma made Itachi
a pacifist who hated war.
そのトラウマは イタチを 争いを好まない
平和を愛する男にした。
里の安定を第一に考え
平和のために働く…。
He was a man who put
the village's safety first,
and who strove to preserve peace.
そういう男だった。
一族という しがらみに
とらわれることなく➡
Instead of being bound
by obligation to his clan,
he was a ninja who loved his village.
里を愛する忍…。
里の上層部は そこを利用した。
And the village higher-ups
preyed on that trait.
上層部は イタチに極秘任務を与えた。
They assigned him to
a top-secret mission.
An eye for an eye...
目には目を…。 うちはに
対抗するには 写輪眼がいる。
For them to oppose the Uchiha,
they would need the Sharingan.
そうだ その任務とは…。
Yes.
The mission was...
うちは一族 全員の抹殺。
The total annihilation of
the Uchiha clan.
そのときのイタチの心情は
どのようなものだったのか…。
I can't even begin to imagine
what he went through emotionally.
想像を絶する。
イタチは 恐るべき選択を
迫られることになった。
Itachi was forced to make
a terrible choice.
The impossible choice of killing
one's own brethren.
同胞に手をかけるなど
ありえぬ返答だったはずだ。
だが うちはほどの忍が
内戦を起こせば➡
But a civil war started by the likes
of the Uchiha would shake
the very foundations of Hidden Leaf Village
and the Land of Fire.
木ノ葉隠れの里も 火の国も
大きく揺らぐ。
Other nations would waste no time
in seizing the opportunity to attack.
それを機に
他国は 必ず 攻め込んでくる。
It could even trigger
a Fourth Great Ninja War...
第四次忍界大戦の引き金にも
なりかねない事態になる。
うちは一族の利己的な思想で➡
The Uchiha clan's self-interest would
involve innocent people
忍の世界とは
無関係な者たちを含め➡
who had nothing to do with
the ninja world.
また多くの人間が死ぬ。
And countless people would die
once again.
お前が イタチなら どうした？
If you were Itachi,
what would you have done?
そこで イタチは決めたのだ。
So Itachi made up his mind.
He himself would bring
the curtain down on his clan.
己の手で 一族の歴史に
幕を下ろすことを。
うちはを憎み
裏切ったのではない。
He did not hate the Uchiha
nor did he betray them.
しかたなかったのだ。
It was inevitable.
里の興りからの差別
そして 確執のツケ。
The discrimination by the village...
and the object of their antagonism...
それを
たったひとりで背負い込み➡
He shouldered the blame all by himself.
No one can ever question Itachi's decision
and the sacrifice he made.
己を犠牲にしたイタチの決断を
責めることは 誰にもできまい。
事実 あの頃のオレも
戦争の機をうかがっていた。
To be truthful, back then,
even I anticipated war.
千手の木ノ葉にも
うちはにも恨みがあったからな。
I was bitter towards Senju's
Hidden Leaf Village as well as the Uchiha.
だが イタチは
それすら気づいていた。
But Itachi was even aware of that.
オレの存在に
唯一 気づいていたのだ。
He alone was aware
of my existence.
イタチは オレに接触を求め
ある条件を出してきた。
Itachi sought to contact me
and made certain conditions.
うちは一族の
復讐の手引きをするかわりに➡
In exchange for guiding me
in my vendetta against the Uchiha,
里側には手を出すなというものだ。
I was not to lay a hand on the village.
同胞を この手にかける
手伝いをすると…。
He would help me kill our brethren...
だが 三代目だけは
別の手を打とうとした。
But the Third Hokage tried
a different hand.
うちはに和解案を打ち出して
話し合いを持とうとしたのだ。
He tried to approach the Uchiha
for a compromise.
だが 時は迫り それは失敗する。
But time ran out,
and his efforts failed.
そして あの夜へと
つながっていく。
Leading to that night.
任務だった。
It was a mission.
To be the sole perpetrator
of his clan's slaughter
一族を殺した犯罪者として➡
and become a Rogue Ninja
with his reputation in tatters.
汚名を背負ったまま
抜け忍となること。
そのすべてが 任務だった。
All of that was his mission.
そして イタチは
その任務を全うした。
And Itachi completely fulfilled
his duty...
ただ一点の失敗を除いてはな。
With one exception...
弟だけは 殺せなかった。
He could not bring himself...
to kill his younger brother.
Truth
その後 イタチは
お前を ダンゾウや上層部から➡
After that, Itachi appealed
to the Third Hokage
守ってくれるよう
三代目 火影に嘆願し➡
to protect you from Danzo
and the higher-ups.
ダンゾウを脅して 里を抜けた。
もし サスケに手を出せば➡
Then he threatened Danzo
and left the village.
If he laid a hand on Sasuke,
里の情報すべてを
非同盟国に暴露すると言ってな。
he would leak every detail about
the village to unallied nations.
お前のことが
何より心配だったのだ。
Above all else,
he was concerned about you.
だが お前に
本当の思いは言えなかった。
And yet he couldn't tell you
the full truth.
だから
ああ言うしかなかったんだ。
He had no choice
but to say the things he did.
((ウソだ！ こんなの
兄さんじゃない!! だって…。
It's a lie...
This isn't like you, Big Brother...
It can't be...
(イタチ)お前が望むような兄を
演じ続けてきたのは➡
I acted like the older brother
you desired...
お前の器を確かめるためだ。
in order to measure your vessel.
お前は オレの器を
確かめるための相手になる。
You will become a rival
to measure my vessel against...
そういう可能性を秘めている。
You have that hidden potential.
お前は オレを
疎ましく思い 憎んでいた。
You've been jealous of me
and resented me.
このオレを超えることを
望み続けていた。
You've harbored hopes
of surpassing me.
だからこそ 生かしてやる。
オレのために。
That is why I am allowing you to live.
For my sake...
愚かなる弟よ。
My foolish little brother...
このオレを殺したくば 恨め。 憎め。
If you wish to kill me,
resent me, hate me.
そして 醜く生き延びるがいい。
And survive...in obscurity.
逃げて逃げて
生に しがみつくがいい。
Run...keep running...
and cling to life.
そして いつか➡
Then one day,
(オレと同じ眼を持って
オレの前に来い!!))
come before me with
the same eye that I possess.
(マダラ)自分への復讐を
目的として与え➡
By making revenge your goal,
he hoped to make you strong.
お前を強くすることを願った。
うちはは 木ノ葉隠れの里の
誇り高き一族だと➡
The Uchiha is a proud clan
of the Hidden Leaf.
そう信じさせておきたかった。
He wanted you to keep
believing that.
本当のことを決して
知られぬよう 火影に願い➡
He beseeched the Hokage that
you never learn the truth.
里を抜けたときより お前と戦い➡
And from the moment
he left the village,
he was resolved to fighting you,
and dying.
死ぬことを心に決めていたのだ。
そのとき
お前に新しい力を与えるため。
So that he could instill in you
a new power.
これがイタチの真実だ。
That is Itachi's truth.
ウソだ… ウソだ！
No, you're lying.
そんなのウソに決まってるだろ。
They must be lies.
デタラメだ。
That's nonsense...
オレは 何度も殺されかけた！
He almost killed me several times!
イタチが本気なら
そうなっていたろう。 確実にな。
If Itachi wished it, he would have.
Without a doubt.
アイツは 万華鏡写輪眼の瞳術まで
使って オレを殺そうとしたんだ！
He even used the Mangekyo Sharingan
to try to kill me!
((あ～っ！))
それなのに。
お前の対処もすべて計算のうちだ。
That's why...!
Your battle was part of his plan.
あの戦いでイタチは
お前を追い込む必要があった。
Itachi needed to pressure you
in that fight.
その理由 本当はお前ももう
気づいているんじゃないのか？
The reason for that...
Well, you probably realized it too,
haven't you?
((出るものが出てきたな))
Finally, it comes out...
呪印からの解放。
He freed you of the curse mark.
そして もっとも親しい者の死。
And the death of someone
closest to you...
お前に万華鏡を
開眼させる戦いでもあった。
It was a battle to awaken
your Mangekyo.
あれはすべて
イタチが仕組んだ戦いだった。
It was a battle that Itachi planned
entirely for your sake.
お前の眼を奪うという芝居を
最後まで演じきってな。
He pretended to be after
your eyes until the very end.
のみ込めてきたようだな。
It's starting to sink in, I see...
お前はウソをついている！
You are lying.
九尾に里を襲わせたのは マダラ！
The one who made the Nine-Tails attack
the village was you, Madara!
お前の仕業だとイタチは言った！
Itachi said so.
Sixteen years ago,
((イタチ : 16年前
九尾が木ノ葉を襲った事件は➡
Madara instigated the Nine-Tails' attack
on Hidden Leaf Village.
マダラが起こしたものだ。
だが それも
四代目に阻止されてしまった。
But that too was foiled
by the Fourth Hokage.
つまり…。
In short...
今のマダラは負け犬だ。
Madara is a bitter, defeated loser...
うちはの本当の高みを
手にするのは ヤツじゃない。
He is not worthy of becoming
the best among the Uchiha.
(あの男 マダラを超え 本当の高みへと
近づくのは このオレだ！))
I am the one...
who shall surpass Madara
and become the ultimate ninja!
お前は うちはに濡れ衣を着せた！
You framed the Uchiha!
イタチと組んで
一族をもてあそぶために！
And you teamed up with Itachi
to toy with the clan!
それは イタチがついたウソだ。
Itachi was lying
when he told you that.
万が一にも
お前に真実が伝わることを➡
Itachi feared that you would
somehow learn the truth.
イタチは恐れていたのだ。
その可能性をみじんも残さぬよう。
He wanted to make absolutely certain
there was no chance of that.
お前にオレを
信用させないためにウソをつき➡
He lied to make sure
you would not trust me...
そればかりか
お前の眼に天照をも仕込んだ。
Not only that,
he implanted Amaterasu in your eyes.
信じられるか そんなこと！
As if I'd believe you!
アイツは イタチは悪だ！
He... Itachi was evil!
一族を殺して
暁に染まった犯罪者だ！
He's a criminal who killed his clan
and joined Akatsuki!
イタチはただ１人
決してぬぐえぬ罪を背負い➡
Itachi took sole responsibility for
an unspeakable crime
里を抜けてなお 暁に入り込み➡
and left the village.
Then he found a way to join Akatsuki
and watched over
里にとって危険な組織を
内部から見張っていた。
an organization that was dangerous
to the village from the inside.
常に 木ノ葉隠れを思いながら。
He was always thinking
about Hidden Leaf Village.
そして同じく お前のことを。
And he thought of you...
お前を守ると約束していた
三代目火影が死んですぐに➡
When the Third Hokage,
who had promised to protect you, died...
イタチが木ノ葉に姿を現したのは➡
Itachi made an appearance
in Hidden Leaf Village.
ダンゾウを含む里の上層部に➡
It was to tell Danzo and
the other superiors that "I am alive."
オレは生きていると
忠告するためだった。
お前のことを何より…。
やめろ！
You were foremost in his thoughts--
Stop! Lies! They're all lies...
ウソだ！ そんなものすべて。
なぜなら お前は生きている。
You're still alive, aren't you?
((人は誰もが 己の知識や
認識に頼り 縛られ 生きている。
In order to survive, we cling to all
we know and understand.
それを現実という名で呼んでな。
And we label it reality.
しかし 知識や認識とは
あいまいなものだ。
But knowledge and understanding
are ambiguous.
その現実は 幻かもしれない。
That reality could be an illusion.
人は皆
思い込みのなかで生きている。
All humans live with
the wrong assumptions.
そうは考えられないか？
Isn't that another way of looking at it?
その写輪眼…
お前は どこまで見えている？
That Sharingan...
How much can you actually see?
My eye is not like it was in the past!
今のオレの眼は 昔とは違う！
オレの写輪眼は 幻術を見抜く！
My Sharingan can see
through genjutsu!
フッ… あいかわらず
強気な物言いだな。
Humph...
You still speak with such confidence.
(その言葉
とりあえず 受け取っておこう))
But for now,
I'll take your word for it.
お前の眼は イタチのことを
何ひとつ見抜けていなかった。
Your eyes did not perceive
a single thing about Itachi.
イタチが作りだした幻を
何ひとつ見抜けなかった。
You were not able to see through
the illusion Itachi created at all.
イタチは 友を殺し 上司を殺し➡
Itachi killed his friends, his superiors...
恋人を殺し 父を殺し 母を殺した。
He killed his lover,
his father and his mother.
だが 殺せなかった。 弟だけは…。
But he could not kill...his little brother.
血の涙を流しながら
感情の一切を殺して➡
He cried tears of blood and
killed every shred of feeling
he had inside him,
里のために
同胞を殺しまくった男が…。
then he killed his brethren
for the sake of his village.
But he just couldn't kill you.
どうしても お前を殺せなかった。
その意味が わかるか？
Do you understand what that means?
アイツにとって お前の命は
里よりも重かったのだ。
To him, your life...
was more precious than the village.
アイツは 死ぬ間際まで…
いや 死んでもなお➡
Until the moment of his death...
No, even in death, it was all for you.
お前のために…
お前に新しい力を授けるために…。
To pass on a new power...
お前に倒されることで
うちは一族の敵を討った。
By making you defeat him,
he had avenged the Uchiha clan.
木ノ葉の英雄に
お前を仕立てあげるために。
In order to raise and make you
the hero of Hidden Leaf Village.
病にむしばまれ
己に近づく死期を感じながら➡
His body was ravaged by illness
and he knew he was near death.
薬で ムリに延命してでも…。
Even if he had to rely on drugs
to prolong his life...
For the sake of
his beloved little brother...
最愛の弟のために…。
お前と戦い お前の前で
死なねばならなかった。
He had to fight you...
and die in your presence.
((マダラ : 木ノ葉の里の平和のため。
For the peace of Hidden Leaf Village,
and most of all, for Sasuke Uchiha.
そして 何より うちはサスケ…
お前のために犯罪者として➡
He wanted to die
as a criminal and a traitor.
裏切り者として
死んでいくことを望んだ。
名誉の代償に汚名を…
愛の代償に憎しみを受け取り…。
He accepted disgrace
in the place of honor,
and hate in the place of love.
それでもなお
イタチは笑って死んでいった。
And despite that, Itachi died
with a smile on his face.
(弟のお前に うちはの名を託し
お前をずっと 騙し続けたまま…))
He entrusted the Uchiha name to you,
his younger brother,
deceiving you to the very end.
((イタチ : ただいま。
I'm home.
兄さん！
Welcome home, Big Brother!
おかえり！
ねぇ 一緒に遊ぼう 兄さん。
Play with me, Big Brother!
ねぇねぇ！ 何して遊ぶ？
Huh? What'll we play?!
コラ サスケ！
Sasuke!
兄さんは
アカデミーの宿題があるんだから➡
Your brother has
Academy homework to do.
それが終わってからにしなさい。
え～。
You can play after he's done.
Huh?
いいよ。 宿題は あとでするから。
That's okay.
I can do my homework later.
簡単だし。
もう…。
It's easy anyway.
Goodness...
《兄さん どこに隠れたのかな？》
Where could Big Brother be hiding?
兄さん 見つけた！
Found you, Big Brother.
なかなか やるな サスケ。
You're pretty sharp, Sasuke.
でも… 残念！
However...too bad.
あ！ ずりぃよ～！
Ah! No fair!
あのね 父さん。
うん？
Say, Father...
Hmm?
今日 兄さんと
かくれんぼしたんだけど➡
Brother and I were playing
hide-and-seek today,
兄さん 分身の術使って
逃げたんだよ。
but Big Brother used Clone Jutsu
to run away.
それって ずるいよね？
That's not fair, is it?
ほう… もう分身が使えるのか。
Hmm... You're able to do
the Clone Jutsu already?
兄さん 食後に
オレにも分身の術 教えてよ！
Big Brother, teach me
the Clone Jutsu too, after dinner!
宿題！
Homework!
もう…。
許せ サスケ。 また今度にしよう。
Sorry, Sasuke.
Let's do it some other time.
サスケ そろそろ帰ろう。
Sasuke. It's time to go.
新しい手裏剣術を
教えてくれるって言っただろう！
You said that you would teach me
a new shuriken jutsu.
(イタチ)明日は
ちょっと大事な任務があって➡
I have an important mission tomorrow
that I must prepare for.
その準備がある。
兄さんのウソつき。
You're a liar...
許せ サスケ。 また今度だ。
Sorry, Sasuke.
Maybe some other time.
イテッ！
兄さん 見てて！ トウ！
Big Brother, watch this!
コラ！ ムチャしたら…。
Hey
兄さん また今度
一緒に修業してくれる？
ああ。
ただ オレも任務を受ける身だし
お前も明日からアカデミーだろ？
２人だけの時間も
そう取れなくなるだろうけどな。
それでもいい。
たまに一緒にいてくれれば。
お前とオレは 唯一無二の兄弟だ。
お前の超えるべき壁として
オレは…。
兄さん。
今日 手裏剣術の修業に
つきあってよ。
オレは 忙しいんだ。
父上にでも教わればいいだろう。
だって 手裏剣術なら
兄さんのほうが上手だって➡
子供のオレでも わかるよ。
イテッ！
許せ サスケ。 また今度だ。
お前の超えるべき壁として
オレは…。
オレは お前とともにあり続けるさ。
たとえ憎まれようとな。
それが兄貴ってもんだ。
(許せ サスケ。 これで最後だ))
我らは 蛇を脱した。
これより我ら小隊は
名を鷹と改め行動する。
鷹の目的は ただ一つ。
我々は…。
木ノ葉を潰す！
＜791年 マグノリア＞
＜ルーシィ : 私たちが
天狼島から戻ってきたら➡
この世界 アースランドでは
７年もの時が経っていた。
昔 そんな童話を
読んだ気がするんだけど➡
まさか 自分が その童話と
同じ体験しちゃうなんて➡
思ってもなかった＞
(みんな)かんぱ～い！
＜ あの夜の
フェアリーテイルでのひとときを➡